{
    "id": "ebf4279727fc45a4989d83413e7ad0df",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "They ……………… the Emperor’s body away on a stretcher.",
            "description": "Bear means carry. Bore is the past tense of bear.",
            "answers": [
                "bore",
                "borne",
                "bored"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1f6af2ca67034e0fa1ea0c13530674af"
        },
        {
            "question": "Thousands of children ………………… blind every year.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are born",
                "are borne",
                "borne"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "65a826fadd7a4409bf35ef49b2b0f763"
        },
        {
            "question": "I want to get married but ………………. I have to find a job.",
            "description": "Either before that or first can be used here.",
            "answers": [
                "before",
                "before that",
                "first"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "29297aa56ef44a41bed9a2a83cd95c79"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will phone before I .....................",
            "description": "In clauses with before, we use a present tense if the meaning is future.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "665c2961514d457c84324159cb9abc1e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the ………………. mangoes?",
            "description": "When other is used with a noun, it does not have a plural form.",
            "answers": [
                "other",
                "others",
                "another"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f8601866b7a147168a43683dfb9caa0c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He looked at me ………………. strange.",
            "description": "Real is possible here in an informal style. This is common in American English.",
            "answers": [
                "real",
                "really",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c8c6c45c17604efabd6f7eb63257f841"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wasn’t ..................... to enter the house.",
            "description": "Let is not usually used in the passive voice.",
            "answers": [
                "allowed",
                "let",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5952e5da3b9742a59c0959751de29bd8"
        },
        {
            "question": "My dog understands everything – he is ………………. human.",
            "description": "Almost can mean ‘similar to, but not exactly the same’.",
            "answers": [
                "almost",
                "nearly",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ef6cecef2f124062beb0e79c324b5432"
        },
        {
            "question": "I met Sally in Germany ………………….",
            "description": "We use ‘ago’ with a past tense and a time expression to count back from the present.",
            "answers": [
                "three years before",
                "three years ago",
                "before three years"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c1075f32f20e4182b59961e3cb84c9f8"
        },
        {
            "question": "The dog was barking ……………..",
            "description": "The article ‘the’ is usually left out in expressions like all day, all night, all week, all summer etc.",
            "answers": [
                "all night",
                "all the night",
                "the all night"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "dccf80610a384d879eae8ee7ed85d45d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would have been in real trouble ………………. your help.",
            "description": "The expression ‘but for’ can mean ‘if something had not happened / existed.",
            "answers": [
                "but for",
                "but",
                "except"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9c0b79ebc1d34a0ca62efa7c290ea5c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "My daughter is not interested in anything but …………….",
            "description": "After ‘interested in’ you need a noun or an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "read",
                "reading",
                "to read"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5b4deae4b74843f0ba1d0c5def825884"
        }
    ]
}